Philip Odhiambo Owino

Tel: +254 721 782 035 E-mail: philipodhis4@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Quality Assurance Specialist with over 3 years of experience. As a specialist, my job entails test planning implementation and execution. Talented in in performance testing and benchmarking. Excellent at quickly identifying high level test strategies and problems. Collaborative but decisive personal style, effective communicator and problem solver.

EDUCATION

2005-2009: Egerton University

BSc. Manufacturing Engineering & Technology

Other Trainings

ISO 9001:2015- Internal auditor training -Smart Method consultant (June 2019)

OSHA training- Pestavic EHS services limited (August 2018)

PLC, Pneumatics & Electro- pneumatics engineering training -Centurion System Limited (2016)

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES ACQUIRED

- Great communication and Interpersonal skills.
- Computer skills.
- High achiever always aiming at the optimum level of performance.
- Ability to Apply a proactive frame of mind and tact to gaining consensus in problem solving.
- Self-motivated and possesses the drive and skill to motivate others.
- Works well in both an independent capacity or as part of a team.
- Good organizational and logistical planning skills.

WORK HISTORY

March 2017 to Date

East Africa Spectre Limited

Quality Assurance & Safety Engineer

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Attending to the Kenya Bureau of Standards technical committee meetings in regard to LPG cylinders.
- Updating and reviewing the company's safety and quality procedures.
- Assisting in machinery maintenance.
- Carrying out safety trainings to the company employees.

- Designing new liquefied petroleum gas cylinders for our clients.
- Attending to all customer complaints that may arise in regard to the company's product.
- Ensuring a strict adherence to all work procedures within the factory floor.

April 2016 - Aug 2017 Kenya Unites Head of Social Media (Volunteer)

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Come up with strategies that would be incorporated in the company's social media platforms.
- Review and development of content for our social media platforms.
- Assist in training personnel in social media strategies.
- Ensure that our social media platforms have the required content at all times.

June 2015-March 2016

Dia Consult Limited

Operations manager

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Plan, control and improve the overall performance of operations.
- Manage quality assurance programs.
- Research on new technologies and alternative methods of efficiency.
- Set and review budgets.
- Come up with strategic objectives to meet the organizational goals.
- Ensure the firm's clients are serviced as per the contract signed by the two parties.

July 2011-Jan 2014

Life Pool Chapel

Head of Logistics (Volunteer)

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Requisition and monitoring of consumable resources.
- Organized and facilitated events and conferences.
- Ensured Routine check of physical assets condition and recommended repair where necessary.
- Came up with the logistics of various activities that the church undertakes.
- Facilitated follow-ups for the new church members.

Jan 2010-June 2011

Online Forex Trader

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Carried out Analysis of economic state of major world economies.
- Technical analysis of currency charts.
- Executed trades as per the analysis made.
- Followed up of major fundamental news of the world major economies

REFEREES

Hudson Chitala

General Manager

East Africa Spectre Limited

Email: <u>Hudson.chitala@easpectre.com</u>

Tel: +254 721724510

Mark Bichachi

Managing Director
Dia Consult Limited

Email: Md@Diaconsultltd.com

Tel: +254 720 604647

Joseph Nzuki

Mechanical Engineer Vivo Energy Kenya

Emails: Joseph.Nzuki@vivoenergy.com

Tel: +254 728114244